Recovery point objective or
恢复点目标或
RPO is the maximum amount of time over which you can lose data.
RPO 是您可以丢失数据的最大时间量
Customers are generating data within your platform,
客户正在您的平台内生成数据
and losing that data after it has been generated is
在生成数据之后丢失数据
even worse than not being able to ingest it in the first place,
更糟糕的是无法在第一个地方摄取
which is what downtime would be.
这就是停工的原因
Thus, we separately track the duration of
因此 我们单独跟踪
time over which we are allowed to lose customer data.
允许我们丢失客户数据的时间
It may sound odd but it's almost always true that losing
听起来很奇怪但几乎总是失去
customer data is worse than not being able to take it in in the first place.
客户数据比在第一个地方无法使用的数据更差
As a customer, would you rather
作为客户 您是否愿意
an online shopping platform not be available for you to place an order,
一个网上购物平台不能给你下订单
or that they take your order but then lose it.
或者他们拿着你的订单就丢了
Don't forget to consider that losing it also
别忘了它也会失去它
likely means that they don't know that you ever submitted the order,
可能意味着他们不知道你提交了命令
and thus, they can't come back to you and ask you for your order again,
所以他们不能再找你问你的命令了
your order will simply never show up.
你的命令根本就不会出现
Most data is lost in one of two ways.
大多数数据以两种方式之一丢失
If your system is up and available to your users but
如果系统已启动并可供用户使用 但
some failure is preventing it from durably storing the information sent to it,
失败的原因是它无法持久存储发送给它的信息
perhaps your database is a 100 percent full,
也许你的数据库是 100%
then you are losing data.
那你就会失去数据
Systems tend to only have one shot at capturing data,
系统在捕获数据时只会有一个镜头
and if they miss it, the data is gone.
如果错过了数据就没了
It may be possible to determine what data is missed
可能可以确定遗漏了哪些数据
by examining logs or other ancillary data sources,
通过检查日志或其他辅助数据源
but this can be tricky,
但这会很棘手
time-consuming, and possibly not 100 percent accurate.
时间消耗 可能不准确 100%
The second way is if you find yourself needing to restore from
第二种方法是如果你发现自己需要从
backup data and your backup is some amount of time old, you will lose data.
备份数据和备份是旧的 您将丢失数据
If you back up your database once an hour,
如果一小时后备份数据库
then your RPO must be at least one hour.
那么 RPO 必须至少为 1 小时
If your backup completes at one o'clock and you
如果您的备份在某个点完成 而您
have massive data corruption occur at 1:45,
大规模的数据腐败发生在 1:45
then to use the one o'clock data means that you will lose 45 minutes worth of data,
那么用一点数据就意味着你损失了 45 分的数据
and the RPO for that incident would be 45 minutes.
而该事件的 RPO 将为 45 分
Having redundant systems is the key to avoiding recovery in the first place.
拥有冗余系统是避免首先恢复的关键
Highly available services keep things running and reduce service disruptions.
高可用性服务可保持运行并减少服务中断
You can use features like
您可以使用类似的功能
S3's version buckets in order to keep older versions of objects.
S3的版本存储区 以保留较旧版本的对象
In the case of data corruption,
在数据损坏的情况下
you can simply undo it and revert to a previous iteration of your data.
您可以将其撤销 并还原为先前的数据迭代
Services like RDS and DynamoDB offer point-in-time data recovery.
类似 RDS 和 DynamoDB 的服务提供时间点数据恢复
This means that they essentially have a continual backup.
这意味着它们本质上具有持续的备份
If you were to experience massive data corruption at 1:45,
如果你在 1:45年经历大规模的数据腐败
you can restore your data to 1:44 and have very little data loss and a very small RPO.
您可以将数据恢复到 1:44  并且数据丢失极少  RPO 很小
Do not overlook the fact that if data corruption occurs
如果发生数据损坏 请不要忽略这一事实
at 1:45 and you don't realize it until 2:15,
1:45 到 2:15
you will still suffer 30 minutes of data loss.
你还会遭受 30 分的数据损失
This is why it is imperative to have strong monitoring and alerting.
因此 必须有强有力的监测和警报